<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lucy Bloomfield</title>
    <description>My little piece of the internet</description>
    <link>http://luchia.com.au/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://luchia.com.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 13:55:40 +1000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 13:55:40 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quade</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Quade was the first foster cat that into our home and he was also one of the most difficult. Nobody knew Quade’s full story but we did know that he had been surrendered to a local pound and he was very near to being put to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/quade/quade-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Quade in the beginning - shy, insecure and distrustful&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quade was the first animal that I have ever thought could experience the emotion love. After many months of getting him comfortable in our home and with us as his carers, there was a trust there that radiated out of his eyes. He was a lap cat, through and through, and would spend as many hours as he possibly could on my partner’s lap while he was gaming or in my arms while I worked on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trefiel.com&quot;&gt;Trefiel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quade taught me compassion for abused beings. It was many months before we were able to love him fully without him flinching or hiding under the couch. He also taught me patience through showing me my tendencies for impatience. Staying present in my dealings with him was difficult a lot of the time, due to outside factors and stress involved in running our business. But ‘stay present’ was a statement I repeated to myself often when sharing our house with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/quade/quade-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Quade in the end - loving, happy but always a little cautious&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of all, Quade brought warmth into our home. Opening the door to see him waiting for us, having cuddles during the day and sharing the bed with him at night are some of my fondest memories with him. And while he may be rehomed and loving his new family, Quade will always be a reminder to me of the ability that beings outside of humans have lessons to teach too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://luchia.com.au/quade</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://luchia.com.au/quade</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Study of the CMD + CTRL customer administrator</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a continuation of my work with Security Innovation on the CMD + CTRL hackathon project. In this case study, you’ll see how I developed the Customer Admin user for this application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand where this project began, let’s take a look at some screenshots of the existing design for this user -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/customer-admin-user/manage-instances.png&quot; alt=&quot;Even though the pages are simple and from a usability standpoint, clear in the required action, the design left a lot to be desired&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/customer-admin-user/navigation.png&quot; alt=&quot;The navigation had a huge amount of options available to the user, many of which could be grouped into related tasks to form an easy to use interface&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/customer-admin-user/register-user.png&quot; alt=&quot;One example of a user task that could have been grouped with others&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/customer-admin-user/bulk-register.png&quot; alt=&quot;Another example of a user task that oculd have been grouped with others&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, I love to start a project with a clear journey for the user. This user was, in particular, very simple in terms of the task needed to be completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/customer-admin-user/user-workflow.png&quot; alt=&quot;The customer admin user workflow was simple and made it easy to create a usable design because of it&#39;s simplicity&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In comparison to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://luchia.com.au/hackathon-participant&quot;&gt;participant user&lt;/a&gt;, this user had a much simpler workflow. In fact, a lot of the bases were covered in terms of design, as I had already hashed out a lot of the structural layout of the application for the participant user. It was simply a matter of organising the tasks in the existing application with consistency to the first user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the time allowed for this project meant that only one portion (the hackathon participant) could be completed fully. Below is as much as I could get done before my time with the company was finished -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/customer-admin-user/launch-pad.png&quot; alt=&quot;The customer admin launch pad - easy access for the things they most need to control&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user logs in and is immediately greeted with the event launchpad. My reasoning for this relates to the nature of the use of the application. The CMD + CTRL application is used in hackathon instances, where a customer admin will manage players as they compete in an event. While they will ocassionally manage users, the weight of their role specifically revolves around the event they are managing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the launch pad, the admin is able to edit any instances of the event. Ideally, I would have liked to remove the repetitive buttons and create a similar workflow as what I had on the original design for the hackathon participant - selecting the instance and controlling it with a row of buttons at the top-right of the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/customer-admin-user/launch-pad-edit.png&quot; alt=&quot;Editing the event&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the instance editor, the user is able to adjust settings for the instance and is able to view what sites are enabled and the event schedule information, all of which are controlled by the super admin. I would have liked to have spent more time consolidating this page design - the two columns to a full-width table below is inconsistent and not as user friendly as I would have liked. I also would have liked to have made it clearer that the event name was an input and it was possible to edit it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/customer-admin-user/manage-instances-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Managing instances of an event - controlling who can use it and when&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From within the view, you’re able to do a few things for the events. Each event will have a number of instances, where it’s running on one or more machines. The customer admin is able to launch all instances (a requirement to start an event), terminate all of them (thereby kicking everyone off) or delete an instance (for management purposes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I particularly like this layout as it goes back to my original participant user design and it’s clear and succinct. With a possibility of having hundreds of instances, having an edit/delete/launch button for each instance is unneccessary. If I had it my way, I would have implemented this on all of the pages (which you will see very soon).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/customer-admin-user/manage-players.png&quot; alt=&quot;Managing players is no longer an exhaustive series of clicks - simple and easy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other actions the customer admin should be able to complete relate to managing users. Similarly to the launch pad, there are excessive links on this page that could have been simplified. I would have liked to had a row of buttons on the top-right hand side of the table, where each user is selectable and able to be managed by those buttons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/customer-admin-user/add-user.png&quot; alt=&quot;Adding a user&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page was put together very quickly and I don’t feel as if it fits the application. If I had more time to complete this project, I would have created a left-hand navigation, similar to the launch pad, where I could manage everything no matter what page I’m on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing that I like about my work on this user is the navigation. The navigation &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; simple but it’s also extremely clear about what the tasks a customer admin can complete. In this respect, I think the application for the customer admin is incredibly simple to use and needs no onboarding or tutorial to get users started with the application. I’m very proud of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this particular user didn’t get a lot of time allocated to it with this project as there was a 4 week sprint for the participant user and not a lot of time left over to complete this user. If I were to come back to this project (hopefully in the near future), I’d love to spend a bit more time on this user and make this part of the application more polished. As you can see from my case study, there is quite a lot I would still change and develop, but overall I am very happy with the simplicity and usability of this interface.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://luchia.com.au/hackathon-customer-admin</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://luchia.com.au/hackathon-customer-admin</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Study of the CMD + CTRL participant user</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things that I love about working with Security Innovation is the variety and depth of projects that I work on. This one was no different. The CMD + CTRL platform is a scoreboard for a ‘hackathon’-styled product that Security Innovation offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’d already built and tested an MVP, but they knew that the design and usability was letting them down. Let’s take a look at why -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/participant-user/navigation.png&quot; alt=&quot;Lack of architecture meant the navigation was convulated and had too many options for users&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/participant-user/purchase-hint.png&quot; alt=&quot;Design, language and general aesthetics were inconsistent&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/participant-user/user-management.png&quot; alt=&quot;Application lacks structure and well-thought out design&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are fairly major issues with their user experience in their initial product. Basically everything that encompasses the user experience - like user journey, information architecture and usability - is non-existant. That’s why they hired me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step for creating a better and more usable application is to understand the user and to give that user a clear path. For this project, there are 3 types of users:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User - Participant in Hackathon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User - Customer Admin (managing participants)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User - Super Admin (managing all user)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now these roles and their functionalities were already decided on so it was a simple matter of picking apart the design and working out the best way for any user to get through the application.The images below are taken from my brief for Security Innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/participant-user/user-journey.png&quot; alt=&quot;How the participant should move through the application&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest part of designing this application was nailing these workflows. These are the backbone of any usable application because it’s not about what a user sees and is able to do, it’s about when a user sees something and that it’s relevant to the point in their journey. &lt;em&gt;This&lt;/em&gt; is key. Having a defined journey means certain things can be hidden at different stages with no effect on the user and we can actually make their experience better by doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next phase was to jump into the design and wireframes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/participant-user/mockup1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Creating the left-hand anchoring early by following a similar pattern on the login/signup page&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/participant-user/mockup3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Using the left-hand side as an anchor, where the right hand-side side is the variable. Setting the precedent of table structures and controls from the beginning.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/participant-user/mockup4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Displaying simple data with tables - the way they should be used&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/participant-user/mockup5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Similar design patterns creates consistency for the application and helps the user stay oriented&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/participant-user/mockup6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Even when controls vary, they remain in the same top-right corner - consistency is key&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/participant-user/mockup7.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tabs can be confusing, but having already them used initially for the login/sign up page, I think they&#39;re use is fine in this case&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent roughly 10 hours coming up with different ideas on loose paper and I kept coming back to this one. For one, the product was always going to be very simple in terms of development - I knew that in any future versions they did, it probably wasn’t going to have a tonne of additions to the navigation and structure of the website. This is why having a side navigation was possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason I thought this design would work is because of the nature of the application. It’s a secondary application that runs besides another application - websites that are hackable, where participants can score points for breaking into them and/or finding their vulnerabilities. This scoreboard application needed to be very simple and very easy to use. In my opinion, having a left-hand navigation makes sense in this case as in the Western world, we read from left to right, making the navigation the first thing the user sees. This orients the user but it also creates a comforting anchor on the left-hand side of the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would also like to discuss my work designing the new user onboard. I always make it my aspiration to design applications that are simple to use and need no tutorial to understand them. However, in this case, I felt that given we had a initial product that was being used by customers already (and we were introducing something completely different), orienting the user in the application was a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We needed to re-confirm the visual cues in the navigation, so I designed a slider that would give context to those in one sentence or less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/participant-user/mockup2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Prompting the user with visual cues helps make clear the intent of the icons in the navigation before the user needs to use them&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, although sliders aren’t fantastic in regards to usability usually, I think in terms of the audience (technically educated users), a slider is fine. As well as this, most users would choose to skip the on-boarding, preferring to jump right in and initiate themselves. As a developer, I know that’s what I do and having conducted user research on many other professional developers, I’ve seen the same thing over and over. The slider is there if you want it, but the application is easy to use on it’s own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I look at this now, I see a lot of inconsistencies and room for improvement. However, with a two week sprint for the design and a two week sprint for the dev, what I came up with in the time given is a great MVP solution. Going forward, I recommend that there is more time spent creating a more consistent application - there is a lot of room for improvement with the sizes of the icons and some of the layouts. However, overall I am very satisfied with where this project finished for a first round.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://luchia.com.au/hackathon-participant</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://luchia.com.au/hackathon-participant</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Designing Trefiel&#39;s Subscription Service</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the hardest things with any product business is ensuring that your customers keep returning. While we have an absolutely incredible product, it’s still difficult for us to do because sheet masks are not a necessary skin care product, at least not like a moisturiser or a cleanser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We knew from our perspective that we needed to find a way to have customers come back to us on a regular time frame, but we also knew that just because we wanted to find a need didn’t mean that we would. So what do you do when you’re trying to develop a new product? You talk to your customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time and time again, we found that women around the world are struggling to make time for themselves. Sure, everyone’s busy, but no one can argue that a mum has a huge amount on her plate - children, partners, family, friends and work. Her own needs? Forget it, when could she possibly find time to fit herself in on her busy days?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our customers told us what they needed. They needed help making a commitment to themselves. They needed a reminder to stop and take some time for themselves. And they needed inspiration to do it - other women around the world who were also juggling busy lives, but found the time to look after themselves regardless. It was just a matter of coming up with a service or product to fit that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subscription model isn’t anything new and watching other people’s success proved to us that this model was viable. We knew that we needed our product to be the centre piece of the service - to have it any other way would weaken the brand and our relationship with our customers. We also knew that it couldn’t just be our product, we needed something extra to entice people to sign up for 6 months or a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that I know, being a woman myself, is that I love to be pampered. I feel fantastic about myself when I indulge in some me-time, specifically if it involves beautifying myself. As much as I like to think I’m a special snowflake, I know deep down that I’m like pretty much every woman out there (in this respect at least). I realised that all we needed to do to make this appeal to our customers was market it right. It wasn’t a ‘sign up and get our masks’ type of service, it was a ‘friendly reminder to look after yourself’ service. And it worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pamper-kit/Pamper_Kit.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Our perfectly packaged Pamper Kit - until it goes through Australia Post&#39;s delivery network&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We packaged it up one afternoon, using tissue paper and ribbon to create a Pamper Kit. Inside the Kit, there were 5 Trefiel Hydromasks, a secondary product to make our customers pamper time extra special and a personal note from Trefiel. Our packaging wasn’t fantastic, but it was enough to get it onto our website and to start marketing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since starting the Pamper Kit, we’ve had a great response and a good numbers. We were offering a free box if customers signed up for a 6 month or one year subscription, however we have since had to remove that offer as a few people took advantage of it - we lost some money on product, but for the most part it was a good lesson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s always room for improvement, which is why this year we’ll be improving packaging to provide an even more luxurious experience for our customers. At the moment, when the Pamper Kit is packaged it looks beautiful, but by the time it’s handled by the postage delivery network, it arrives at their homes looking a little worse for weather. We want to provide the ultimate experience and we’ll do this by continuing to work on our design of the service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://luchia.com.au/trefiel-service-design</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://luchia.com.au/trefiel-service-design</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trefiel&#39;s Social Media Strategy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Trefiel, like most new businesses, relies heavily on marketing to drive business and sales. Our initial plan was to be an entirely online business, as Michael and I both wanted to continue traveling while working on the business. The most obvious case of online marketing is, of course, social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that initially gave us the push to start Trefiel was seeing hundreds of small businesses make it big on Instagram. We knew it was possible to do, even with grammar and spelling mistakes that we saw all over their accounts and websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We modelled our initial marketing plan off the success of others - repurposing content and making it fit our brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/social-media/repurosed-content.png&quot; alt=&quot;Repurposing other people&#39;s content to create a brand&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what we soon found out was Instagram had changed significantly since these same businesses had had their success. It’s full of other small businesses trying to do exactly what we were doing - reusing other people’s content to promote our product. The platform was and is saturated and trying to differentiate yourself by doing the same thing as everyone else wasn’t going help us stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I knuckled down on our messaging. While before we’d share a wide range of content (kittens, food, funny quotes, photos, donuts, vacation destinations), now we started on focusing on two very clear things - skin care and self-love. I didn’t realise how all over the place our messaging was until I started enforcing these two requirements for our content. Immediately, you can see a difference in our Instagram feed and how it all ties in together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/social-media/selective-content.png&quot; alt=&quot;Being more selective with content resulted in a more cohesive story&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time I thought “Eureka! I’ve worked it out!”. But as we continued following this formula, we still saw the same issues we were having with when we were re-using content - low engagement and slow growth. One thing I’ve found since starting Trefiel is that running a business is constant revising of the things you thought you knew about it. I thought I’d solved the problem of our engagement, but I had only made a baby step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next step was to deploy mirror marketing - we harnessed the power of social media by delivering hundreds of samples around the country to key influencers. Some of these were paid (more on that later), but hundreds were not. We spent hours and hours on Instagram finding suitable women to send product to. Our key requirements were that they had to be a reasonable photographer, they needed to have a following of 5000 or more and they needed to be based in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think about how many Instagram accounts are currently in use, we had a very broad criteria that meant we could sent out a huge amount of samples to numerous women. Because we didn’t knuckle down on who we wanted, we were able to target so many different women and it actually turned out to be a good thing. Immediately, we saw results - higher traffic, higher engagement and a huge increase in growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/social-media/influencer-content.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sending out hundreds of samples helped us gain exposure&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We noticed something fascinating. As a new company, we rely heavily on word of mouth and experiences from users. Posts that mentioned our company with an @ tag only converted poorly, where full scale reviews - multiple paragraphs describing the users experience - were three times as effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the nature of Instagram, we never knew when we were going to get a post from an influencer - images were often being posted every couple of days, which ended up working out quite well for us. This enabled us to track the success of our posts and influencers, leading to hiring a number of girls to post regularly for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much of our success has been establishing key relationships where the demographic of influencer suits our own intended target audience. Another huge part of our success has been our market saturation. We literally flooded the Australian market with our masks and even started to adapt our influencer requirements, lowering the number of followers to 1000 so we could get the product into more people’s hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we found with influencers who had under 1000 followers was particularly interesting. If the influencer was young, the mask generally didn’t convert with their audience. But slightly older women, say from 25 and up, the mask converted decently. Why? We realised that even though these women didn’t have huge reach to hundreds and thousands of people, they did have reach within their community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as this, most older women are not approached by companies asking to give them free samples, whereas with younger women it is quite common. It meant the product in their feeds was more natural, as they didn’t often advertise products and it also made it possible to convert some of our influencers who we sent free product too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/social-media/customers.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our customers and influencers were sharing awesome content and helping solidify us as a real brand&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this stage, we’d tried paying a few major influencers with varying success. One in particular is extremely successful for us and we continue tow work with her on a 6 month contract, where she posts about our product and helps us promote our current marketing campaigns. Others have been less successful - we spent $1000 on an influencer only to get 3 sales (about ~$110).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We felt that our inexperience had potentially lead us to choosing influencers that weren’t particularly suited to our product, so we spent a lot of time revising who we actually wanted to connect with and what we had to offer them. We didn’t hire influencers for over a month, as we figured all of this out. When we were finally ready to go again, it took weeks to find suitable candidates and work with their agencies to come up with a good deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/social-media/customerss.png&quot; alt=&quot;Not all influencers are created equal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It bombed. In fact, they all bombed. It was incredibly frustrating as we had spent so many hours trying to revise our requirements and searching for particular influencers. My thoughts on this are that most influencers honestly don’t have THAT much influence over their audiences. Sure people follow them, they like their photos, they occasionally comment - but for the most part, what that person says and does has no effect on their audiences life. For us going forward, paid influencers are a thing we do very cautiously and we would rather skip it while working on other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What worked intitially with the unpaid influencers has since stopped working as well, which I knew would happen eventually. We’re no longer new and we have developed quite a trusting relationship with our audience, so posts that were reviews were starting to get less and less engagement. I noticed this, but I didn’t change anything because I knew that while we may not be able to share those captions anymore, we could still use the photos from influencers and the exposure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/social-media/creative-content-b.png&quot; alt=&quot;When our influencer tactic stopped working, we started creating our own content&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we did start something new. One of the systems we have installed in the backend of our website sends follow up emails once a customer has purchased. We have a survey email that goes out after 3 weeks, asking key questions about our customer and the things they’d like to know. We found so many people wanting to know more about us - who was behind Trefiel and what happened behind the scenes. Not everyone, but a significant portion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people that answer this question wanting to know more about us are identified as our key customers. They want to know more about us, they love the mask and they love us as a company. They’re our raving fans and while we may not have 1000, by marketing to people that love us and our company, we can attract others like them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I created a new marketing plan, where we aimed to shoot more of our own content to tell our story about Trefiel. Initially, I thought this would be a secondary content type to our customers images, but what we found blew my initial thoughts out of the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/social-media/creative-content.png&quot; alt=&quot;Original, beautiful content went nuts and drove a tonne of growth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People loved it. Even more than our customer photos. So what initially started out as a few hours on Fridays, shooting and editing content, became a full day of shooting, with editing being done over the weekend (for the following weeks content).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content we started producing was initially very rough and not as professional as I would have liked. In fact, I look at the things I shot just a few weeks ago and I see massive room for improvement. But it’s exciting! This type of content is perfect because we’re trying to differentiate ourselves on the Instagram platform and we do this by simply telling our story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve found videos have huge results and people love seeing Michael and I joking around for our promotional videos. The posts that I thought would be least successful have turned out to be the most successful and each week I’m learning something new about the business and the customers we’re trying to serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now our feed features specific customers and/or influencers that either have fantastic photos or are key influencers that will provide us with leverage when acquiring new customers. As well as this, we’ve swapped most of the customer image photos captions for #skintips - captions where we help our audience to improve their skin. These are hints about our masks and tips that we have for better results, or just general suggestions for better skin in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s where we’re at now, but I have hundreds of ideas for how to continue improving our social media efforts and our marketing in general. As we gain more experience, I see the value of providing incredible content more and more. It’s not easy to start a business and it’s certainly not easy to market a business, especially when you’re playing the same game as everyone else. Differentiating ourselves by letting our personality shine through our content has lead to MASSIVE growth and engagement, something which I’m really proud of having been the lead on all of our marketing efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://luchia.com.au/trefiel-social-media</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://luchia.com.au/trefiel-social-media</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The First Version</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was coming home on the tram from a meet up the other day. This in itself isn’t very exciting but I do enjoy being in a city where there are so many types of people around. People-watching is both constructive and meditative, especially if approached from a non-judgemental aspect (FYI, it’s not people-watching if you’re making criticisms, it’s being a jerk).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I was watching a girl, over her shoulder, write a text on her phone. I know this is terrible and I’m a snoop, but I couldn’t help it. What she was doing was fascinating. You see, she really liked Will and even though they weren’t (at that moment) talking about their feelings, I could tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched this girl rewrite her message fives times before it was acceptable to send. The first time she admitted to eating leftovers out of the fridge, but that was deleted. The second time she went the mum route and told him she should eat breakfast, but that was also deleted. The final message was a suggestion for him to try the olive sourdough/spinach/egg/tomato/bocconcini/olive oil/salt/pepper combo because it would change his life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t comment on the last version of the text message (that breakfast sounds amazing to me), but I found it exhilarating to watch as this girl edited away her responses until it was perfect. A perfect response so that she seemed perfect. The connotations I took from that message was that she eats well, she cooks and she’s healthy and that’s probably what Will took from it too. But I got to see the previous versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that she’s just like any person, who goes the easiest route at breakfast time and reaches for leftovers. I know she’s nervous and she likes Will a lot, but she doesn’t want to come across as too clingy. I know she’s scared that the first version of herself isn’t enough and she needs to provide an edited response. Most of all, I know she desperately wants to be loved because I watched her check her messages 10 times, waiting for his response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appearances aren’t everything and the way people choose to portray themselves is often an edited response, changed by the pressure of wanting to fit in and be liked. I know that I did this a lot before I went traveling and still occasionally do, but the older I get the more I find that being myself is far more fun than editing myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NB: I didn’t even edit this post. First version FTW.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://luchia.com.au/the-first-version</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://luchia.com.au/the-first-version</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spring Chaos</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Spring is my favourite time of the year. The sun starts to burn a little, the days warm up yet the nights are still cool. I sometimes still get a rainy day to lay in bed on the weekends (or week days), but there’s also the beautiful clear days that should only be spent racing through the mountains on a motorbike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I’ve been writing regularly for myself, I haven’t touched this blog in months, let alone had the desire to craft a well-written post. Although there have been posts created in 2015, reading them back I realise they lack the special spark that makes this corner of the internet, mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where did Lucy go? Simply put, I was too busy living my life to write about and document it. This year I’ve spoken at multiple conferences, I lived in the Middle East (amazing place, would go back there in a heartbeat), learnt to ride a motorbike, learnt how to pole dance, had surgery, learnt how to cook (properly) and moved to a new city. I’ve explored my identity and the ways in which I express myself, my communication channels, my relationships and my flaws. I’ve even managed, although I still struggle with it, to remove myself entirely from social media, excluding business accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of my not wanting to write for this blog has been paired with my desire to remove myself from social media. I didn’t want to share my posts on platforms, receive gratification by the various notification systems or receive congratulations from friends and family. I didn’t want to feel as if this blog was for anyone else but myself, and I think given my current metrics (a big 0 visitors for the last however many months), this is now possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be writing from now on about the things which interest me because they are many and varied. I want to write more about the cities I visit while traveling and the people I meet every day. I want to write and learn through my social experiments and share my thoughts on the books I’m reading. Mostly, I want to use this as a brain dump, a collection of thoughts and feelings, as a reminder of how quickly things can change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I call this spring chaos because I feel like the whole concept of ‘spring cleaning’ and the end of the year drives people to do wild things - review their life, say things that haven’t been said, finish half-completed things and make big changes. In that respect, I’m not all that unusual.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://luchia.com.au/spring-chaos</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://luchia.com.au/spring-chaos</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
