<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lucy Bloomfield</title>
    <description>My little piece of the internet</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 14:54:34 +1000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 14:54:34 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Designing Trefiel's Subscription Service</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the hardest things with any product business is ensuring that your customers keep returning. While we have an absolutely incredible product, it’s still difficult for us to do because sheet masks are not a necessary skin care product, at least not like a moisturiser or a cleanser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We knew from our perspective that we needed to find a way to have customers come back to us on a regular time frame, but we also knew that just because we wanted to find a need didn’t mean that we would. So what do you do when you’re trying to develop a new product? You talk to your customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time and time again, we found that women around the world are struggling to make time for themselves. Sure, everyone’s busy, but no one can argue that a mum has a huge amount on her plate - children, partners, family, friends and work. Her own needs? Forget it, when could she possibly find time to fit herself in on her busy days?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our customers told us what they needed. They needed help making a commitment to themselves. They needed a reminder to stop and take some time for themselves. And they needed inspiration to do it - other women around the world who were also juggling busy lives, but found the time to look after themselves regardless. It was just a matter of coming up with a service or product to fit that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subscription model isn’t anything new and watching other people’s success proved to us that this model was viable. We knew that we needed our product to be the centre piece of the service - to have it any other way would weaken the brand and our relationship with our customers. We also knew that it couldn’t just be our product, we needed something extra to entice people to sign up for 6 months or a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that I know, being a woman myself, is that I love to be pampered. I feel fantastic about myself when I indulge in some me-time, specifically if it involves beautifying myself. As much as I like to think I’m a special snowflake, I know deep down that I’m like pretty much every woman out there (in this respect at least). I realised that all we needed to do to make this appeal to our customers was market it right. It wasn’t a ‘sign up and get our masks’ type of service, it was a ‘friendly reminder to look after yourself’ service. And it worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pamper-kit/Pamper_Kit.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Our perfectly packaged Pamper Kit - until it goes through Australia Post's delivery network&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We packaged it up one afternoon, using tissue paper and ribbon to create a Pamper Kit. Inside the Kit, there were 5 Trefiel Hydromasks, a secondary product to make our customers pamper time extra special and a personal note from Trefiel. Our packaging wasn’t fantastic, but it was enough to get it onto our website and to start marketing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since starting the Pamper Kit, we’ve had a great response and a good numbers. We were offering a free box if customers signed up for a 6 month or one year subscription, however we have since had to remove that offer as a few people took advantage of it - we lost some money on product, but for the most part it was a good lesson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s always room for improvement, which is why this year we’ll be improving packaging to provide an even more luxurious experience for our customers. At the moment, when the Pamper Kit is packaged it looks beautiful, but by the time it’s handled by the postage delivery network, it arrives at their homes looking a little worse for weather. We want to provide the ultimate experience and we’ll do this by continuing to work on our design of the service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/trefiel-service-design</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/trefiel-service-design</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trefiel's Social Media Strategy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Trefiel, like most new businesses, relies heavily on marketing to drive business and sales. Our initial plan was to be an entirely online business, as Michael and I both wanted to continue traveling while working on the business. The most obvious case of online marketing is, of course, social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that initially gave us the push to start Trefiel was seeing hundreds of small businesses make it big on Instagram. We knew it was possible to do, even with grammar and spelling mistakes that we saw all over their accounts and websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We modelled our initial marketing plan off the success of others - repurposing content and making it fit our brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/social-media/repurosed-content.png&quot; alt=&quot;Repurposing other people's content to create a brand&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what we soon found out was Instagram had changed significantly since these same businesses had had their success. It’s full of other small businesses trying to do exactly what we were doing - reusing other people’s content to promote our product. The platform was and is saturated and trying to differentiate yourself by doing the same thing as everyone else wasn’t going help us stand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I knuckled down on our messaging. While before we’d share a wide range of content (kittens, food, funny quotes, photos, donuts, vacation destinations), now we started on focusing on two very clear things - skin care and self-love. I didn’t realise how all over the place our messaging was until I started enforcing these two requirements for our content. Immediately, you can see a difference in our Instagram feed and how it all ties in together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/social-media/selective-content.png&quot; alt=&quot;Being more selective with content resulted in a more cohesive story&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time I thought “Eureka! I’ve worked it out!”. But as we continued following this formula, we still saw the same issues we were having with when we were re-using content - low engagement and slow growth. One thing I’ve found since starting Trefiel is that running a business is constant revising of the things you thought you knew about it. I thought I’d solved the problem of our engagement, but I had only made a baby step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next step was to deploy mirror marketing - we harnessed the power of social media by delivering hundreds of samples around the country to key influencers. Some of these were paid (more on that later), but hundreds were not. We spent hours and hours on Instagram finding suitable women to send product to. Our key requirements were that they had to be a reasonable photographer, they needed to have a following of 5000 or more and they needed to be based in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think about how many Instagram accounts are currently in use, we had a very broad criteria that meant we could sent out a huge amount of samples to numerous women. Because we didn’t knuckle down on who we wanted, we were able to target so many different women and it actually turned out to be a good thing. Immediately, we saw results - higher traffic, higher engagement and a huge increase in growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/social-media/influencer-content.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sending out hundreds of samples helped us gain exposure&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We noticed something fascinating. As a new company, we rely heavily on word of mouth and experiences from users. Posts that mentioned our company with an @ tag only converted poorly, where full scale reviews - multiple paragraphs describing the users experience - were three times as effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the nature of Instagram, we never knew when we were going to get a post from an influencer - images were often being posted every couple of days, which ended up working out quite well for us. This enabled us to track the success of our posts and influencers, leading to hiring a number of girls to post regularly for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much of our success has been establishing key relationships where the demographic of influencer suits our own intended target audience. Another huge part of our success has been our market saturation. We literally flooded the Australian market with our masks and even started to adapt our influencer requirements, lowering the number of followers to 1000 so we could get the product into more people’s hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we found with influencers who had under 1000 followers was particularly interesting. If the influencer was young, the mask generally didn’t convert with their audience. But slightly older women, say from 25 and up, the mask converted decently. Why? We realised that even though these women didn’t have huge reach to hundreds and thousands of people, they did have reach within their community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well as this, most older women are not approached by companies asking to give them free samples, whereas with younger women it is quite common. It meant the product in their feeds was more natural, as they didn’t often advertise products and it also made it possible to convert some of our influencers who we sent free product too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/social-media/customers.png&quot; alt=&quot;Our customers and influencers were sharing awesome content and helping solidify us as a real brand&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this stage, we’d tried paying a few major influencers with varying success. One in particular is extremely successful for us and we continue tow work with her on a 6 month contract, where she posts about our product and helps us promote our current marketing campaigns. Others have been less successful - we spent $1000 on an influencer only to get 3 sales (about ~$110).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We felt that our inexperience had potentially lead us to choosing influencers that weren’t particularly suited to our product, so we spent a lot of time revising who we actually wanted to connect with and what we had to offer them. We didn’t hire influencers for over a month, as we figured all of this out. When we were finally ready to go again, it took weeks to find suitable candidates and work with their agencies to come up with a good deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/social-media/customerss.png&quot; alt=&quot;Not all influencers are created equal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It bombed. In fact, they all bombed. It was incredibly frustrating as we had spent so many hours trying to revise our requirements and searching for particular influencers. My thoughts on this are that most influencers honestly don’t have THAT much influence over their audiences. Sure people follow them, they like their photos, they occasionally comment - but for the most part, what that person says and does has no effect on their audiences life. For us going forward, paid influencers are a thing we do very cautiously and we would rather skip it while working on other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What worked intitially with the unpaid influencers has since stopped working as well, which I knew would happen eventually. We’re no longer new and we have developed quite a trusting relationship with our audience, so posts that were reviews were starting to get less and less engagement. I noticed this, but I didn’t change anything because I knew that while we may not be able to share those captions anymore, we could still use the photos from influencers and the exposure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/social-media/creative-content-b.png&quot; alt=&quot;When our influencer tactic stopped working, we started creating our own content&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we did start something new. One of the systems we have installed in the backend of our website sends follow up emails once a customer has purchased. We have a survey email that goes out after 3 weeks, asking key questions about our customer and the things they’d like to know. We found so many people wanting to know more about us - who was behind Trefiel and what happened behind the scenes. Not everyone, but a significant portion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people that answer this question wanting to know more about us are identified as our key customers. They want to know more about us, they love the mask and they love us as a company. They’re our raving fans and while we may not have 1000, by marketing to people that love us and our company, we can attract others like them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I created a new marketing plan, where we aimed to shoot more of our own content to tell our story about Trefiel. Initially, I thought this would be a secondary content type to our customers images, but what we found blew my initial thoughts out of the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/social-media/creative-content.png&quot; alt=&quot;Original, beautiful content went nuts and drove a tonne of growth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People loved it. Even more than our customer photos. So what initially started out as a few hours on Fridays, shooting and editing content, became a full day of shooting, with editing being done over the weekend (for the following weeks content).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content we started producing was initially very rough and not as professional as I would have liked. In fact, I look at the things I shot just a few weeks ago and I see massive room for improvement. But it’s exciting! This type of content is perfect because we’re trying to differentiate ourselves on the Instagram platform and we do this by simply telling our story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve found videos have huge results and people love seeing Michael and I joking around for our promotional videos. The posts that I thought would be least successful have turned out to be the most successful and each week I’m learning something new about the business and the customers we’re trying to serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now our feed features specific customers and/or influencers that either have fantastic photos or are key influencers that will provide us with leverage when acquiring new customers. As well as this, we’ve swapped most of the customer image photos captions for #skintips - captions where we help our audience to improve their skin. These are hints about our masks and tips that we have for better results, or just general suggestions for better skin in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s where we’re at now, but I have hundreds of ideas for how to continue improving our social media efforts and our marketing in general. As we gain more experience, I see the value of providing incredible content more and more. It’s not easy to start a business and it’s certainly not easy to market a business, especially when you’re playing the same game as everyone else. Differentiating ourselves by letting our personality shine through our content has lead to MASSIVE growth and engagement, something which I’m really proud of having been the lead on all of our marketing efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/trefiel-social-media</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/trefiel-social-media</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
