<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lucy Bloomfield</title>
    <description>I don&#39;t know what I do anymore but I don&#39;t really care either. I design things, I cook and eat, I photograph and write about the places that I&#39;m in.</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 15:03:15 +1100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 15:03:15 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Morning Rituals That Make Me Feel Accomplished</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s already a vast collection of articles written about successful people and their morning habits, but I’m not a celebrity entrepreneur and no one knows what I do every morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last 6 months, I’ve been using myself as a bit of guinea pig and experimenting with different actions and noticing the effects they have on me. At this stage, I feel like I’ve really nailed my morning routine and feel comfortable with the feeling of accomplishment it gives me and also the state of mind it leaves me in to finish my day. I thought it could be interesting to share what I do and potentially open up some discussion in regards to ways I could improve my day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-the-bed&quot;&gt;Make the bed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I only do one thing a day, it’s got to be this. Leaving the house knowing this is done makes me feel like I’ve done the smallest thing right, even if everything else goes wrong. I’ve noticed if I do this, I notice other small things that go right and become more appreciative of those. More appreciation = greater happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-up-early&quot;&gt;Getting up early&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a drag doing this recently, especially when I spend the night with my partner talking strategy for Trefiel, but without a doubt this is a huge contributor to how I feel about my day and how much I get done. When I’m up early, the whole day lies ahead of me - glittering and full of possibility. I get the quiet of the mornings, where no one is awake and there are no interruptions. I also get an exceptionally good nights sleep when i stay in routine and wake up early every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;exercise&quot;&gt;Exercise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prime time to do cardio. I’m trying a split at the moment that requires 2 workouts a day, but for only 20 minutes each - the goal being to train with extremely high intensity in two short bursts. I can definitely attest to the success I’m having with this at the moment as I’m 21% body fat and leaner than I’ve ever been. Getting a dose of endorphins before I sit down to work also helps with my concentration and ability to retain information. I’ve noticed that if I listen to podcasts or University material while I exercise, I have higher retention of the information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fasting&quot;&gt;Fasting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something I’ve been playing with consistently for about a month now, although I have done it previously. Fasting is a god-send when you’re dropping weight. For one thing, you only have a short period of time that’s open for eating, which means fitting in the days calories becomes a much more difficult thing. Instead of spreading my calories over an entire day (3 meals plus snacking), I fit it into an 8 hour window that usually consists of 2 meals plus minimal snacking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing is the concentration gained from not thinking about food constantly. I know that I can’t be the only one that struggles with this. Once I start eating, I think about my next meal constantly and am dealing with hungry pains all day. Making this phase shorter has lessened it’s impact on my life but also given me extreme clarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lemon-water&quot;&gt;Lemon Water&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is related to fasting. I enjoy the way this beverage makes me feel in the mornings while I’m waiting for my fasting period to end. A lot of people like tea and coffee while fasting because it does quell hunger pains, but I’m steering clear of caffeine at the moment (another thing that I think helps with concentration) and for me this is just as good. It’s 100x better with coconut oil in it, but isn’t everything?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this gives people some ideas about habits that actually work to improve focus and accomplishments achieved. I’d be interested to hear if anyone has any suggestions about other things I could try to improve my morning rituals further.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 03:52:07 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/morning-rituals</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/morning-rituals</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        <category>habits</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The First Version</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was coming home on the tram from a meet up the other day. This in itself isn’t very exciting but I do enjoy being in a city where there are so many types of people around. People-watching is both constructive and meditative, especially if approached from a non-judgemental aspect (FYI, it’s not people-watching if you’re making criticisms, it’s being a jerk).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, I was watching a girl, over her shoulder, write a text on her phone. I know this is terrible and I’m a snoop, but I couldn’t help it. What she was doing was fascinating. You see, she really liked Will and even though they weren’t (at that moment) talking about their feelings, I could tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched this girl rewrite her message fives times before it was acceptable to send. The first time she admitted to eating leftovers out of the fridge, but that was deleted. The second time she went the mum route and told him she should eat breakfast, but that was also deleted. The final message was a suggestion for him to try the olive sourdough/spinach/egg/tomato/bocconcini/olive oil/salt/pepper combo because it would change his life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t comment on the last version of the text message (that breakfast sounds amazing to me), but I found it exhilarating to watch as this girl edited away her responses until it was perfect. A perfect response so that she seemed perfect. The connotations I took from that message was that she eats well, she cooks and she’s healthy and that’s probably what Will took from it too. But I got to see the previous versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that she’s just like any person, who goes the easiest route at breakfast time and reaches for leftovers. I know she’s nervous and she likes Will a lot, but she doesn’t want to come across as too clingy. I know she’s scared that the first version of herself isn’t enough and she needs to provide an edited response. Most of all, I know she desperately wants to be loved because I watched her check her messages 10 times, waiting for his response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appearances aren’t everything and the way people choose to portray themselves is often an edited response, changed by the pressure of wanting to fit in and be liked. I know that I did this a lot before I went traveling and still occasionally do, but the older I get the more I find that being myself is far more fun than editing myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NB: I didn’t even edit this post. First version FTW.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 03:52:07 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/the-first-version</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/the-first-version</guid>
        
        
        <category>melbourne</category>
        
        <category>observations</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spring Chaos</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Spring is my favourite time of the year. The sun starts to burn a little, the days warm up yet the nights are still cool. I sometimes still get a rainy day to lay in bed on the weekends (or week days), but there’s also the beautiful clear days that should only be spent racing through the mountains on a motorbike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I’ve been writing regularly for myself, I haven’t touched this blog in months, let alone had the desire to craft a well-written post. Although there have been posts created in 2015, reading them back I realise they lack the special spark that makes this corner of the internet, mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where did Lucy go? Simply put, I was too busy living my life to write about and document it. This year I’ve spoken at multiple conferences, I lived in the Middle East (amazing place, would go back there in a heartbeat), learnt to ride a motorbike, learnt how to pole dance, had surgery, learnt how to cook (properly) and moved to a new city. I’ve explored my identity and the ways in which I express myself, my communication channels, my relationships and my flaws. I’ve even managed, although I still struggle with it, to remove myself entirely from social media, excluding business accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of my not wanting to write for this blog has been paired with my desire to remove myself from social media. I didn’t want to share my posts on platforms, receive gratification by the various notification systems or receive congratulations from friends and family. I didn’t want to feel as if this blog was for anyone else but myself, and I think given my current metrics (a big 0 visitors for the last however many months), this is now possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be writing from now on about the things which interest me because they are many and varied. I want to write more about the cities I visit while traveling and the people I meet every day. I want to write and learn through my social experiments and share my thoughts on the books I’m reading. Mostly, I want to use this as a brain dump, a collection of thoughts and feelings, as a reminder of how quickly things can change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I call this spring chaos because I feel like the whole concept of ‘spring cleaning’ and the end of the year drives people to do wild things - review their life, say things that haven’t been said, finish half-completed things and make big changes. In that respect, I’m not all that unusual.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 03:52:07 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/spring-chaos</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/spring-chaos</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        <category>observations</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What it&#39;s like to work remotely</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the last three to four months, I’ve spoken at quite a few conferences about working remotely. In Australia, this concept hasn’t really come into play that much yet and I think one of the main reasons for this is that we don’t have a large start up scene here and a lot of the companies designers and developers work for are brick and mortar types (ie. very old-fashioned).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve really enjoyed sharing what working remotely is, how good it is and how to do it efficiently which is something I know a lot about thanks to the team at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.securityinnovation.com&quot;&gt;Security Innovation&lt;/a&gt;. As I wrapped up my last talk on working remotely at Decompress, Melbourne, I thought I’d do a summary post of what it’s like to work remotely and why I love working for SI so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-working-remotely&quot;&gt;What is working remotely?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s when you complete you work in a place other than your employees office. It can be working from home, from a co-working space or while travelling - as I did for the last 12 months. It’s becoming a more and more viable solution to the productive worker conundrum, giving freedom and responsibility to the employee while cutting down costs and improving output for the employer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-i-become-a-remote-worker&quot;&gt;How do I become a remote worker?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a freelancer, then you can arrange a remote working situation quite easily by re-adjusting your clients and the way you work. If you’re employed, then it’ll be a little different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, you should concentrate on improving your productivity and performance at work. This can include 4HWW principles such as having an auto-responder on emails defining response times, skipping meetings and using your most productive parts of the day to get large tasks done. Once you’ve increased productivity and it’s been noticed, suggest to your employer that you’d like to try a trial period where you work one day a week from home. Save a little bit of productivity for when you go home - that is, work better at home - and continue to be productive in the office. The rest is negotiating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people ask me about how to become a remote worker and the easy answer is to ask. The worst thing your employer can say to you is no. If you pitch it right and have proven that you can do your work and do it well, the whole telecommuting concept is not a strange or uncommon request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pros-and-cons&quot;&gt;Pros and Cons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be completely honest about what it’s like to work remotely. The cons are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Communication is hard (no sharing paper sketches, no brainstorming together)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Timezone differences&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Company culture is hard to maintain because there’s no water cooler to meet at&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Workaholicism&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It can be lonely working from home&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travelling and finding good internet can be difficult depending on where you are&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The positives of working remotely:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You have fantastic work life (balance, picking hours, appointments)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Costs are lower&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting away from distractions (but it’s still easy to procrastinate)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wearing your pyjamas to work has its bonuses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increased productivity (10-20% more productive)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working remotely is not just beneficial for employees though. From a company perspective, the pros are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Increased productivity, remote workers log more hours than their office-based colleagues (Gallup’s State of American Workplace)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You have access to more talent, better talent and can find it at a faster rate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Costs dramatically reduced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Respond to ‘oh shit’ moments quicker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the cons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s hard to find people who are good at working remotely&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Company culture isn’t built naturally (you’ve got to work for it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-to-day-routine&quot;&gt;Day-to-day routine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I only work four days a week, which for me, is the perfect balance between work and play. This is one of the things I enjoy most about working remotely - I can work when I feel like it. My average day will look something like this-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5am - Wake up + coffee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5.10am - Laptop on, headphones in&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8am - Meeting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;9am - Misc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10am - Work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2pm - Misc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4pm - Work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5pm - Bedtime - Misc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, I’ve got a time throughout my day to step away from my work and reset.  Some days I’ll go to the gym twice, read, go see friends, nap, design for side projects, draw, photograph things… whatever I feel like doing.  Some days I work straight through from 5am until 1pm so I have the afternoon and night free.  As long as the work is done, the hours that I work can be spread throughout my day however I like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;software&quot;&gt;Software&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s thanks to technology that I’m able to work the way I do. Most remote workers have a basic set up that’s fairly similar, so I won’t spend too long on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skype (meetings)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wunderlist (personal task manager)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Github (Git) (work task manager)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gmail (communication)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Calendar (meetings)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Join.me (screen sharing)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slack (collaboration, company culture)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This set up is not without it’s faults. For example, we could use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trello (team task manager)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Hangouts (combined meetings, screen sharing, collaboration, company culture)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the development team, we leverage Github for team collaboration. We have a team of developers working on this project around the clock so it’s really important that our repos are up-to-date.  We have a repo for the project and within that repo we have a number of different branches.The first branch is master and is the source code that the project is deployed from. The second branch is Dev, which is the branch all team members eventually merge their own separate branches onto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then have all of our own separate branches to work on individually. This means that no ones code gets left behind on merges or disappears due to other team members pushing or pulling code. The final type of branch we have relates to specific issues on Github which require more than one team member to work on it. By doing this, we move the code to a place that is easily shared between team members and can be worked on without affecting the original code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have a set up which has automatic testing. As soon as a push is made to Github, our tests are running on Travis. This allows us to see immediately if our changes have broken tests and if they have, we write new tests to cover them. We’ve managed to cover everything, right down to CSS styles, and currently have a 98% code coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;time-management&quot;&gt;Time Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to think that because you’re working from home, it’ll be easier to get distracted and you’ll get less work done. I also thought the same thing but once you’re in the situation and the work &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be done, you do it. Something that I’ve noticed is that I procrastinate more in the office than I do at home.  I used to work in the law industry and most of my day was spent responding to emails and googling, which are essentially the work-force’s approved form of procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a couple of small things that really help improve my productivity:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I use page blockers on my browser so that I cannot get distracted. (Reddit, Facebook, Instagram, Gmail, Twitter)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have a routine that I stick to most days which keeps me on track.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I think it’s important to learn how to properly priorities your work - what needs to be done now, what needs to be done today and what should be done tomorrow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s been said many times, but Social Media can be one of the biggest distractions we have. I limit my time on social media ruthlessly and am much happier and more productive for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;work-life-balance&quot;&gt;Work-Life Balance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as we have creative jobs and projects to work on, it’s still important to make time to work on things outside of the scope of your job. Whether this is part of an 80/20 rule with the company you work for or you spend your weekends writing a novel, having creative side projects that are started to fuel your passion will ensure that your work doesn’t become unenjoyable. There’s always going to be more work to do and emails to read, so for the sake of your sanity take your leisure time as seriously as you do your work time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing that I highly recommend for work-life balance and overall happiness is travel. Not only will you be exposed to new cultures and foods, you’ll meet people that you wouldn’t have otherwise. I speak from experience when I say this - my two biggest job offers last year were chance occurrences where I just happened to be in the right place, at the time. Travel is also a great way to balance your day because you work for part of the day and spend the rest exploring a new city or meeting new people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, whenever you have the chance - disconnect from the world. Switch off your computer, your phone, everything. Go sit outside in the park and watch the clouds float by. Meditate and think about the something outside of your small circle - for me, that’s space - and remind yourself that no matter what’s happening in your life, it too will pass.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 02:52:07 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/working-at-security-innovation</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/working-at-security-innovation</guid>
        
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
